# 广东·中山
# 1月份拍摄
2 Today, we’re going to a manor for dinner.
# 今天我们还是到一个庄园来吃饭
3 At the place where we are standing, we can hear those geese are honking.
# 在这个地方 我们就能听到鹅的叫声
4 We’re having roast goose today.
# 我们今天要去吃的是 果木烤鹅
5 That guy told us to head over there.
# 刚才叔叔告诉我们 要朝这边走
6 Now, let’s get into the restaurant.
# 接下来我们要去找吃饭的地方
7 So many fishes in the pond.
# 一进来就看到了好多鱼
8 But, they’re all decorative fishes.
# 不过都是观赏性的鱼
9 are they bought just for decoration?
# 这是专门买的鱼吧
10 This countryside manor has everything
# 这一个农家庄园 真的是什么都有
11 Over there, is for the geese to get roasted.
# 这边呢 就是做烧鹅的
12 Right here, they are making Tofu skin and Sesame balls.
# 看我前面就是在做腐竹 还有做煎堆的
13 They have a large variety of food here.
# 各种各样的菜品都能在这里找得到
14 This countryside manor has 4 or 5 kitchens
# 这个农家园光厨房就有四五个
15 stir fry dish, roast goose, and pastry.
# 炒菜 做烧鹅 做糕点
16 every chef is working on their own station.
# 每个师傅好像都有自己的任务在这个地方忙
17 The thing right behind me is a few dozens of tiny ovens.
# 我后面就是几十个金钟罩
18 Right there.
# 里面就是
19 Every each of that ovens contains a goose.
# 每一个炉子里面都有一只鹅
20 those golden-brown geese are dripping goose fat.
# 它们金黄诱人 还流着肥油
21If an ordinary goose
# 一只平平无奇的鹅
22 wants to because shinny in appearance
# 想要变得如此光鲜亮丽
23 It needs to go through a lot more than that.
# 还得经历一些的磨难
24 A cleaned goose has to be inflated, boiled, and blanched with cooking oil.
# 洗净的鹅要吹气 滚水 烫皮
25 and then, they stuff the goose with marinates.
# 然后 才能够把腌料 塞进肚子里
26 At this moment, the goose is no different expect it has been inflated.
# 这个时候的鹅 从外面看 除了变得气鼓鼓的
27 it looks like nothing has changed.
# 好像没有什么样的变化
28 But the aroma of the marinates are spreading all over the meat.
# 但是腌料的味道 正在向全身蔓延
29 It needs to be dried,
# 这个鹅得先在后面进行风干处理
30 before it goes into the oven.
# 然后才能够上烤炉
31 that goose is going to spin in that oven
# 它要在里面 转呀 转呀 转呀
32 for a good hour.
# 转足一个小时 才能够下来
33 In this massive manor,
# 在偌大的庄园里
34 spinning geese are catching all the spotlights.
# 一只只烤鹅转圈圈的场景成为了全场的焦点
35 Although, we can only see the bottom part of the geese.
# 虽然说 我们只能看到它的下半身
36 After an hour of roasting on low heat,
# 经过长时间的文火烤制
37 The skin color of those geese is darkening.
# 鹅外皮的颜色会逐渐加深
38 Also, the aroma of meat and fruit wood are thickening.
# 果木香和肉香 也变得更加浓郁
39 When geese are ready, chefs will slice the meat into this shape.
# 烤鹅做好了 师傅要把它片成这种片状
40 after slicing,
# 片完之后呢
41They will pour a spoon of goose stock.
# 还要在上面浇一勺的汤汁
42 It just made the goose so much tempting.
# 这样才能感觉到更加诱人
43 this glass is soundproofed right? I can’t hear anything.
# 玻璃是隔音的吧 什么也听不到
44 but I can see that goose inside.
# 只能看着眼馋
45 the ground level is packed, lets head to the second floor.
# 一楼都坐满了 我们现在要上二楼了
46 I wasn’t expecting tea here.
# 没想到来庄园吃饭 还要喝茶
47 I ordered some regular tea.
# 我们就是要了一个很普通的茶
48 Let’s order some food.
# 然后现在就是点单
49 They provide a QR code for food ordering.
# 它这边是扫码点单
50 Let’s see what they got.
# 咱们看一看有什么好吃的
51 I didn’t know they
# 不看不知道
52 got everything.
# 真的是什么都有
53 The goal of this trip is to try their roast goose.
# 咱们这次来的
目的是
吃烧鹅
54 So, I have to order that roast goose.
# 所以一定点
烧鹅
55 I’m getting some side dishes as well.
# 其它的
便点点吧
56 the goose itself looks pretty big.
# 看烧鹅就挺大的了
57 What a tiny candle.
# 好小的蜡烛
58 they gave us candles to keep the dish warm.
# 给了一个加热的蜡烛
59 not bad.
# 挺好的
60 The length of the plate for this goose
# 这个放烤鹅的盘子
61 is almost
# 长度呢 差不多会有我的
62 60 centimeters.
# 四扎吧 用我的手来比划的话
63 I’m using my hand to measure it
# 差不多是四扎的长度
64 This is a half of the goose.
# 这只是半只 就是这么长
65 the skin of is shining, if I look closely,
# 烧鹅的外皮 油亮油亮的 仔细看
66 there is a very thin layer of fat between the mean and the skin.
# 肉和皮之间还有一层很薄的脂肪层
67 Before a goose got served for eating,
# 一只鹅被端上餐桌之前
68 It has to be inflated, dried, roasted.
# 要经过吹气 风干 刷皮水 烤制等过程
69 Without the moisture in the skin,
# 表皮没有那么多的水分
70 it just tastes much crispier and crunchier.
# 烤完之后吃起来 会有微弱的脆的口感
71 and the meat inside
# 而包裹在里面的鹅肉
72 will taste juicier and more tender
# 吃起来鲜嫩 而且多汁
73 Actually, every bite is quite fatty.
# 每一块的鹅肉 其实都是很肥腻的
74 So, you need some sweet and sour dipping sauce.
# 这个时候呢 你可以来点酸甜口的酱料
75 or some savory sauce.
# 也可以来点咸口的酱料
76 but no matter which kind of sauce you chose.
# 但是不管是哪种口味的
77 you can get rid of some of the greasy taste.
# 对于它来说 都是解腻的
78 No matter how rich and various the food is,
# 不管菜品再丰富
79 You need a bowl of rice to finish the meal
# 最后都得归结于一碗白米饭
80 Therefore, you can get fulled
# 这样才能够感觉吃得饱
81 This goose is way to big, I couldn’t even finish a half of it
# 这个鹅实在是太大了 半只都没有吃了
82 We’re taking the goose drumstick home.
# 我们要把大块的鹅腿带走了
83 I almost lost track of direction on the way out.
# 走出来都差点没有找到路
84 This place is massive.
# 这个地方太大了
85 Please subscribe to my channel! Xue Yu
# 关 注
# 雪 鱼 探 店